Inventory of the J. Herbert Furth papers
Hoover Institution Archives
J. Herbert Furth papers
1923-1995
96032
Hoover Institution Archives
20 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (8.0 linear feet)
Speeches and writings, correspondence, and printed matter, relating to economic theory, and especially to laissez-faire economics and associated concepts of liberty.
Furth, J. Herbert (Joseph Herbert), b. 1899.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1996.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
October 12, 1899: Born in Vienna, Austria
1918-1923: Studied law and social science at University of Vienna; founded Association of Democratic Students with Friedrich A. Hayek.
1938: Immigrated to the United States
1938-1939: Studied at Harvard University as “Special Student”
1939-1943: Professor of Economics, Lincoln University, Pennsylvania
1943-1966: Economist and Advisor to the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System
1943-1966: Lecturer in Economics, American University
1945-1950: Lecturer in Economics, Catholic University
1949: Consultant, International Bank for Reconstruction and Development
1960: Visiting Professor of International Finance, International University of Luxembourg
1967-1968: Research Staff, National Bureau of Economic Research
1967-1974: Faculty Associate in Residence, Foreign Service Institute
March 6, 1995: Died, Chevy Chase, Maryland
Related Collection(s)
Friedrich A. von Hayek Papers, Hoover Institution Archives; Gottfried Haberler Papers, Hoover Insitution Archives
Scope and Content of Collection
This collection consists of speeches and writings, correspondence, and printed matter, relating to economic theory, and especially to laissez-faire economics and associated concepts of liberty. The collection is divided into seven sections, including a Biographical File, Academic Career File, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve File, Speeches and Writings, Writings by Others, Correspondence, and Printed Matter.
Haberler, Gottfried, 1900-; Hayek, Friedrich A. von (Friedrich August), 1899-1992.; Economics.; Economists.; Laissez-faire.; Liberty.
- Biographical File, circa 1960s
  - Curriculum Vitae, circa 1960s (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Excerpt from article related to Furth, undated (Box-folder 1: 2)
- Academic Career, 1968-1993
  Scope and Contents note
  Comprised of correspondence, notes, and biographical materials related to Furth's teaching career at various universities including Catholic University, American University, International University of Luxembourg, and the Foreign Service Institute.
  - Contractual documents, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Daily class schedule, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Exam outline, undated (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Student rosters, 1984 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1983
    - Dalton, James E., 1981 (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - Harrington, John M., 1979-1983 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Course Materials, 1970-1982
    - History of Economic Thought course materials, 1982 (Box-folder 1: 9)
    - History of Economic Thought course syllabus, 1982 (Box-folder 1: 10-11)
    - International Economics II course syllabus, 1970, 1972 (Box-folder 1: 12-13)
    - International Economics II course materials, 1972 (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - International Finance and the American Worker, lecture notes, circa 1970s (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Seminar Notes, 1968-1993
    - "An Austrian Look at Supply-Side Economics,", 1981 (Box-folder 1: 16)
    - "Balance of Payments,", 1977 (Box-folder 1: 17)
    - "Borchardt: Business Cycles, Pre-1974 and Post-1949," (Box-folder 1: 18)
    - "Carter Murphy: International Monetary System,", 1980 (Box-folder 1: 19)
    - "Current Problems of International Finance Policy,", 1981 (Box-folder 1: 20)
    - "The Decline of U.S. Productivity,", 1979 (Box-folder 1: 21)
    - "Eric Voegelin's 'In Search of Order,'", 1987 (Box-folder 1: 22)
    - "Fellner & Stein on Problems of Inflation,", 1980 (Box-folder 1: 23)
    - "Foreign Dollar Balances,", 1975 (Box-folder 1: 24)
    - "Haberler on the International Monetary System,", 1977 (Box-folder 1: 25)
    - Hayek, circa 1970s (Box-folder 1: 26)
    - "Hayek: Denationalization of Money,", 1976 (Box-folder 1: 27)
    - "Hayek on Liberalism and Democracy,", 1978 (Box-folder 1: 28)
    - "Hayek's Attack on the Concept of Social Justice,", 1977 (Box-folder 1: 29)
    - "Ideology vs. Common Sense,", 1990 (Box-folder 1: 30)
    - "In Defense of Schumpeter's Vision,", 1980 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - "Introduction to International Economics,", 1968 (Box-folder 2: 2)
    - "J. Robinson: What Are the Problems?,", 1978 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - "J. Ziegler: Switzerland,", 1980 (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - Liberalism, 1989 (Box-folder 2: 5)
    - "Michael Harrington, Decade of Decision,", 1980 (Box-folder 2: 6)
    - "Problems of Immigration,", 1978 (Box-folder 2: 7)
    - "A Refugee Looks at the U.S.,", 1988 (Box-folder 2: 8)
    - "The Relevance of Goethe's Faust,", 1986 (Box-folder 2: 9)
    - "The Share of Capital Income in U.S. Economy,", 1976 (Box-folder 2: 10)
    - "Two New Attempts at Finding the 'Middle Way,'", 1979 (Box-folder 2: 11)
    - "U.S. Balance of Payments,", 1977 (Box-folder 2: 12)
    - Unidentified, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 2: 13-14)
- Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, 1942-1989
  Comprised of correspondence, notes, and reports related to Furth's role as advisor to the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve.
  - Diagram of the organization of the Division of Research and Statistics, with related correspondence, 1942-1945 (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Commentary on the writings of Patrick M. Boarman, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - Commentary of the writings of N. Walter, with related correspondence, 1974 (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - Commentary on economics paper on Italian economy, 1964 (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - General notes, undated (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - Memoranda, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - Correspondence and clippings related to history of Board of Governors, 1989 (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - "Austrian Finance," report, 1948 (Box-folder 2: 22)
  - "Balance of Payments and Capital Movements," speech, 1964 (Box-folder 2: 23)
  - "The Dilemma of U.S. Monetary Policy," report, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 24)
  - "Federal Reserve Holdings of Foreign Exchange,", 1961 (Box-folder 2: 25)
  - "Financial Problems of Liberated Europe," report, 1945 (Box-folder 2: 26)
  - "Free Market vs. Party Rates," report, 1948 (Box-folder 2: 27)
  - "Full Employment and Monetary Stability," report, 1951 (Box-folder 2: 28)
  - "Germany's Foreign Trade - An Objective Lesson in Economic Sanity," report, 1950 (Box-folder 2: 29)
  - "The International Position of the U.S. Dollar," report, 1961 (Box-folder 2: 30)
  - "John Exeter on the U.S. Balance of Payments," report, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 31)
  - "Money and Banking in Liberated Belgium," report, 1945 (Box-folder 2: 32)
  - "Mr. Exeter on the U.S. Payments Deficit - II," report, 1965 (Box-folder 2: 33)
  - "Problems of Silver Coinage," report, 1964 (Box-folder 2: 34)
  - "Problems of the U.S. Balance of International Payments," report, 1961 (Box-folder 2: 35)
  - "Professor Triffin and the Problem of International Monetary Reform," report, 1961 (Box-folder 2: 36)
  - "Review of Foreign Developments," report, 1953 (Box-folder 2: 37)
  - "Review of Foreign Developments," report, 1957 (Box-folder 2: 38)
  - "Review of Foreign Developments," report, May 27, 1958 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - "Review of Foreign Developments," report, November 25, 1958 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - "The U.S. Balance of Payments - Present and Future," report, 1964 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - "U.S. Payments Deficit and Domestic Economy," report, 1964 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - "Unbalanced International Accounts - Diagnosis and Therapy," report, 1960 (Box-folder 3: 5)
- Speeches and Writings, 1932-1989
  Comprised of reports, articles, monographs, and drafts written by Furth on various topics related to economics.
  - Address in thanks of building staff, 1984 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - "Bankenkrach in U.S.A.,", 1933 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - "Die Bankenwesen in U.S.A.,", 1932 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - "Barriers to Direct Investment in Europe as Tools of the U.S. Payments Policy,", 1968 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - "Capitalism," film strip drafts, notes, and related correspondence, 1983-1984, undated (Box-folder 3: 10-11)
  - "Central Bank Policies and Economic Equilibrium,", 1950 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - "The Dilemma of U.S. Monetary Policy,", 1962 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - "Earnings and Unemployment in the Business Cycle,", 1942 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - "Epilogue to Bretton Woods,", 1977 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  - "Erinnerungen an Wiener Tage,", 1989 (Box-folder 3: 16)
  - "International Developments and Monetary Policy,", 1964 (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - "International Dollar Liquidity and the Eurodollar Market," with related correspondence, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - "International Liquidity - Problems and Solutions,", 1963 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - Invitation to speech given by Furth, 1932 (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - "The Machlup Report - A Critical Evaluation,", 1964 (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - "On United Nations Economics,", 1960 (Box-folder 3: 22)
  - "Praktische Aufgabe der Recht-Soziologie,", circa 1930s (Box-folder 3: 23)
  - "Professor Triffin on the Problem of International Monetary Reform,", 1962 (Box-folder 3: 24)
  - Review of "Economic Survey of Europe in 1949,", 1950 (Box-folder 3: 25)
  - Review of "Economic Survey of 1950, Economic Survey of 1951,", 1952 (Box-folder 3: 26)
  - Review of "A History of Economic Reasoning,", 1984 (Box-folder 3: 27)
  - Review of "An International Economy: Problems and Prospects,", 1959 (Box-folder 3: 28)
  - "Short Run Escape Clauses of the Havana Charter,", 1949 (Box-folder 3: 29)
  - "Some Problems of International Payments Reform,", 1963 (Box-folder 3: 30)
  - "Supply-Side Economics: A Preliminary Report,", 1981 (Box-folder 3: 31)
  - "The U.S. Balance of International Payments,", 1962 (Box-folder 3: 32)
  - Untitled paper on U.S. trade deficit, circa 1970s (Box-folder 3: 33)
- Writings by Others, 1929-1994
  Comprised of monographs, articles, and reports written by other economists with whom Furth associated in the course of his work.
  - Aliber, Robert Z., 1973 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Allen, Loring, 1983-1992 (Box-folder 4: 2-4)
  - Allen, Polly R., 1979 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Andel, Norbert, 1975 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Aoki, Masano, 1977 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Armey, Dick, circa 1980s (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Barker, T. S., 1974 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Black, Stanley W., 1976 (Box-folder 4: 10-11)
  - Böhm, Franz, 1976 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - Böhm, Stephan B., 1989-1993, undated (Box-folder 4: 13-15)
  - Braga de Macedo, Jorge, 1982 (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - Branson, William H., 1975-1976 (Box-folder 5: 1-5)
  - Brown, Weir M., 1976 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Browne, Martha Steffy, 1976-1984 (Box-folder 5: 7-9)
  - Bruno, Michael, 1979 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Burns, Joseph M., 1976 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Butenandt, Adolph, 1984 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Calmfors, Lars, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 5: 13-15)
  - Calvo, Guillermo, 1978 (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - Canzoneri, Matthew B., 1981-1984 (Box-folder 5: 17-18, 6: 1)
  - Capiro, Jerry, 1981 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Christiernin, P. N., 1971 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Darity, William, Jr., 1984 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Deardoff, Allen V., 1978 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Dunn, Robert M., Jr., 1973-1983 (Box-folder 6: 6-7)
  - Dulles, Eleanor Lansing, 1978 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - van Duyne, Carl, 1978 (Box-folder 6: 9-10)
  - Edison, Hali J., 1985 (Box-folder 6: 11-12)
  - Eichengreen, Barry J., 1979 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - Eidem, Rolf, 1976 (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - Ericsson, Neil R., 1985 (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - Ethier, Wilfred J., 1975-1985 (Box-folder 6: 16-17)
  - Falcoff, Mark, 1983 (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - Fellner, William, 1982 (Box-folder 6: 19-21)
  - Findlay, Ronald, 1976 (Box-folder 6: 22-23)
  - Flood, Robert P., 1981 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Ford, Gerald, 1977 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Gerloff, Wilhelm, 1963 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Gerschenkron, Alexander, 1978 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Girton, Lance, 1976 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Goode, Richard, circa 1980s (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Grassman, Sven, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 7: 7-11)
  - Gray, Jo-Anna, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 7: 12-14)
  - Haberler, Gottfried, 1929-1992 (Box-folder 7: 15-26, 8: 1-8)
  - Hamilton, Carl, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 8: 9-14)
  - Hayek, Friedrich A., 1948-1984 (Box-folder 8: 15-24, 9: 1-3)
  - Henderson, Dale W., 1979 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - Herberg, Horst, 1978 (Box-folder 9: 5-6)
  - Hersey, Arthur, 1981 (Box-folder 9: 7)
  - Hession, Charles H., 1984 (Box-folder 9: 8)
  - Hooper, Peter, 1980 (Box-folder 9: 9)
  - Houthakker, Hendrik S., 1976 (Box-folder 9: 10)
  - Howe, Howard, 1976 (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - Ingram, James C., 1973 (Box-folder 9: 12)
  - Isard, Peter, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 9: 13-15)
  - Jacobson, Laurence, 1981 (Box-folder 9: 16)
  - Jaffe, Dwight M., 1975-1976 (Box-folder 9: 17-18)
  - Kahn, Herman, 1983 (Box-folder 9: 19)
  - Kaufmann, Felix, 1992 (Box-folder 9: 20)
  - Kawai, Masahiro, 1980 (Box-folder 9: 21)
  - Kemp, Jack, 1976 (Box-folder 9: 22)
  - Kenen, Peter B., 1975-1983 (Box-folder 10: 1-2)
  - Kindleberger, Charles P., 1951 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - Kleiman, Ephraim, 1975 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  - Knauer, Elfriede, 1976-1984 (Box-folder 10: 5-10)
  - Pentti, J. K., 1976 (Box-folder 10: 11-14)
  - Lambrecht, Frank L., 1976 (Box-folder 10: 15)
  - Lapan, Harvey, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 10: 16 - 11: 1)
  - Leith, J. Clark, 1977 (Box-folder 11: 2)
  - Lenczowski, George, 1976 (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - LeRoy, Stephan F., 1975 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - Leube, Kurt R., 1988-1989 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - Lindbeck, Assar, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 11: 6-15)
  - Lowinger, Thomas C., 1976 (Box-folder 11: 16)
  - McCullah, Rachel, 1983 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Machlup, Fritz, 1973-1982 (Box-folder 12: 2-8)
  - Maneschi, Andrea, 1994 (Box-folder 12: 9)
  - Mann, Fritz Karl, 1976 (Box-folder 12: 10)
  - Marquez, Jaime, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 12: 11-14)
  - Mason, William E., 1981-1989 (Box-folder 12: 15 - 13: 2)
  - Meese, Richard, 1985 (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - Meissner, Frank, circa 1970s (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - Menger, Karl, 1983 (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - Merrett, Stephen, 1976 (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - Michalopoulos, Constantine, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 13: 7-8)
  - Michaels, James W., 1983 (Box-folder 13: 9)
  - Mikesell, Raymond F., 1975 (Box-folder 13: 10)
  - Mills, Rodney H., 1979 (Box-folder 13: 11)
  - Mintz, Ilse, 1974 (Box-folder 13: 12)
  - von Mises, Ludwig, 1981, undated (Box-folder 13: 13-14)
  - Mitchell, Edward J., 1975 (Box-folder 13: 15)
  - Muellbauer, John M., 1975-1978 (Box-folder 13: 16-17)
  - Myhrman, Johan, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 13: 18-20)
  - Myrdal, Gunnar, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 14: 1-2)
  - Nyberg, Lars, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 14: 3-6)
  - Obstfeld, Maurice, 1981 (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - Overhoff, Julius, 1977 (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - Parkinson, Patrick M., 1982 (Box-folder 14: 9)
  - Perlman, Mark, 1993 (Box-folder 14: 10)
  - Pollack, Gerald A., 1975 (Box-folder 14: 11)
  - Portes, Richard, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 14: 12-13)
  - Radetzki, Marian, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 14: 14-15)
  - Roosa, Robert V., 1983 (Box-folder 14: 16)
  - Sampson, Gary P., 1979 (Box-folder 14: 17)
  - Schönfeld-Illy, Leo, 1924 (Box-folder 14: 18)
  - Schumpeter, Joseph, 1979 (Box-folder 14: 19)
  - Shea, Gary S., 1985 (Box-folder 14: 20)
  - Snape, Richard H., 1974 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - Söderström, Hans Tson, 1977 (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - Stein, Herbert, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 15: 3-4)
  - Stolper, Wolfgang, 1982-1995 (Box-folder 15: 5-11)
  - Svensson, Lars E. O., 1976-1977 (Box-folder 15: 12 - 16: 1)
  - Symansky, Steven A., undated (Box-folder 16: 2)
  - Taquey, Charles H., 1984 (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - Taubman, Paul, 1972 (Box-folder 16: 4)
  - Viotti, Staffan, 1978 (Box-folder 16: 5)
  - deVreis, Egbert, 1974 (Box-folder 16: 6)
  - Wallich, Henry C., 1979 (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - Walters, A. A., 1985 (Box-folder 16: 8)
  - Wells, Donald A., 1976 (Box-folder 16: 9)
  - Whitson Fetter, Frank, 1977 (Box-folder 16: 10)
  - Wihlborg, Clas, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 16: 11-12)
  - Willett, Thomas D., 1975 (Box-folder 16: 13)
  - Wilson, John F., circa 1983 (Box-folder 16: 14)
  - Yeats, Alexander J., 1977 (Box-folder 16: 15-16)
  - Unidentified, 1955-1985, undated (Box-folder 16: 17-20)
- Correspondence, 1934-1994
  Comprised primarily of Furth's correspondence with other economists on topics related to economics and their writings.
  - List of addresses, undated (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - From Harrington, John M., Jr., to Friedrich A. Hayek, 1981 (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - From Harrington, John M., Jr., to Philip Lawler, 1982 (Box-folder 17: 3)
  - From Mason, William E., to Irving Kristol, circa 1980s (Box-folder 17: 4)
  - From Stolper, Wolfgang, to Gottfried Haberler, 1993 (Box-folder 17: 5)
  - Machlup vs. Jokl lawsuit correspondence and court documents, 1934-1944 (Box-folder 17: 6)
  - Allen, George V., 1968 (Box-folder 17: 7)
  - Bryant, Ralph C., 1980 (Box-folder 17: 8)
  - Coulbois, Paul, 1980 (Box-folder 17: 9)
  - Furth, Werner F., 1969 (Box-folder 17: 10)
  - Haberler, Gottfried, 1973-1994 (Box-folder 17: 11-12)
  - Hart, Parker T., 1969 (Box-folder 17: 13)
  - Haugerud, Howard E., 1971 (Box-folder 17: 14)
  - Holland, Robert, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 17: 15)
  - Junz, Helen B., 1980 (Box-folder 17: 16)
  - Kelley, E. W., 1989 (Box-folder 17: 17)
  - Lansing Dulles, Eleanor, 1980 (Box-folder 17: 18)
  - Loring, Allen, 1984 (Box-folder 17: 18)
  - McChesney Martin, William, Jr., 1984 (Box-folder 17: 20)
  - McComber, William B., 1971 (Box-folder 17: 21)
  - Marget, Edith, 1980 (Box-folder 17: 22)
  - Mason, William E., 1981-1984 (Box-folder 17: 23)
  - Mathews, Elbert G., 1971 (Box-folder 17: 24)
  - von Mises, Margit, 1981 (Box-folder 17: 25)
  - Moss, Milton, 1986 (Box-folder 17: 26)
  - Pantazopoulos, N. J., 1976 (Box-folder 17: 27)
  - Polak, J. J., 1962, 1980 (Box-folder 17: 28)
  - Pribram, Edith, 1980 (Box-folder 17: 29)
  - Samuelson, Paul A., 1992 (Box-folder 17: 30)
  - Scott, Ira O., Jr., 1968 (Box-folder 17: 31)
  - Smith, Clint, circa 1960s (Box-folder 17: 32)
  - Sollenberger, Howard E., 1970-1971 (Box-folder 17: 33)
  - Stolper, Wolfgang, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 17: 34)
  - Struc, Ernest, 1980 (Box-folder 17: 35)
  - Taquey, Charles H., 1984 (Box-folder 17: 36)
  - Weisskopf, Walter A., circa 1970s (Box-folder 17: 37)
  - Wood, Ralph, 1980 (Box-folder 17: 38)
  - Unidentified, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 17: 39)
- Printed Matter, 1923-1993
  - Boletin Internacional, 1976 (Box-folder 18: 2)
  - C.V. Starr Center for Applied Economics Newsletter, 1983 (Box-folder 18: 3)
  - "The Crisis in Economics and the Hong Kong Response,", 1984 (Box-folder 18: 4)
  - Current Problems in International Monetary Policy, 1961 (Box-folder 18: 5)
  - Democratic Solidarity: Proposals for the 1984 Democratic Party Platform on Foreign Policy and National Defense, pamphlet with related correspondence (Box-folder 18: 6)
  - "The Economist,", 1993 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - Federal Reserve for Saint Louise Review, 1969 (Box-folder 18: 8)
  - Festschrift für Otto von Simson zum 65. Geburtstag, circa 1970s (Box-folder 18: 9)
  - Gerichts-Zeitung, 1928 (Box-folder 18: 10)
  - Handwörterbuch der Sozial-wissenschaften, 1956 (Box-folder 18: 11)
  - Hayek, F. A. interview in Encounter, 1983 (Box-folder 18: 7)
  - Horizontal Divestiture: Highlights of a Conference on Whether Oil Companies Should be Prohibited from Owning Nonpetroleum Energy Resources, 1977 (Box-folder 18: 12)
  - In Memoriam: Professor Frits J. de Jong, 1977 (Box-folder 18: 13)
  - "International Economic Conditions: Annual Data 1963-1982,", 1983 (Box-folder 18: 14)
  - The Journal of Marketing, with related notes, 1940 (Box-folder 18: 15)
  - The Journal of Political Economy, 1956 (Box-folder 18: 16)
  - Juristische Blätter, 1928-1935 (Box-folder 21: 2)
  - Law and Contemporary Problems, 1969 (Box-folder 18: 17 - 19: 1)
  - "Meet the Press," transcript of interview with F. A. Hayek, 1975 (Box-folder 19: 2)
  - Mont Pèlerin Society, newspaper clippings, 1977 (Box-folder 19: 4)
  - The National Economy 1975 (Box-folder 19: 3)
  - Niveaux des développment et politiques de croissance, 1956 (Box-folder 19: 5)
  - "Oasia Listing of Recent, Unpublished Manuscripts in International Economics and Economic Development,", 1975 (Box-folder 19: 6)
  - Oestereichische Anwalts-Zeitung, 1928-1933 (Box-folder 19: 7-8)
  - Österreichische Richterzeitung, 1934 (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Political Observer, 1976 (Box-folder 19: 9)
  - The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 1959 (Box-folder 19: 10)
  - Recession, Inflation, and How to Overcome Both, circa 1970s (Box-folder 19: 11)
  - Die Rechtsprechung, 1928 (Box-folder 21: 3)
  - Regulatory Reform: Highlights of a Conference on Government Regulation, 1975 (Box-folder 19: 12)
  - "Report of the Subcommittee on International Economics of the Joint Economic Committee Congress of the United States,", 1974 (Box-folder 19: 13)
  - Review of Economics and Statistics, 1942, 1952 (Box-folder 19: 14)
  - Revista Brasileira de Economica, 1949 (Box-folder 19: 15)
  - Scheidewege, 1978, 1981 (Box-folder 19: 16)
  - "Schumpeter - In his Own Words,", 1983 (Box-folder 19: 17)
  - Social Science Fellowships of the Rockefeller Foundation, 1933 (Box-folder 19: 18)
  - "State of the Economy and Policies for Full Employment," transcript, 1962 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Studies in Economic Theory, 1978 (Box-folder 20: 2)
  - The Three Banks Review, with related notes, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 20: 3-4)
  - U.S. News and World Report, 1976 (Box-folder 20: 5)
  - Weltwirtschaftliches Archiv, 1973 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - Westermanns Monatshefte, 1970 (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - William Fellner memorial pamphlet, 1983 (Box-folder 20: 8)
  - Wirtschaftsforschungsinsitut 50th anniversary article, 1977 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - World Economic Outlook, 1984 (Box-folder 20: 9)
  - World Politics: A Quarterly Journal of Interational Relations, 1959 (Box-folder 20: 10)
  - Yale Law Journal, 1932 (Box-folder 20: 11)
  - Zeitschrift für Nationalökonomie, 1936 (Box-folder 20: 12)
  - Zeitschrift für Volkswirtschaft und Sozialpolitik, 1923 (Box-folder 20: 13)
  - Zentralblatt für Juristisches Praxis, 1927-1948 (Box-folder 20: 14)
  - The 1973 Joint Economic Report (Box-folder 20: 15)
- Eleanor Lansing Dulles curriculum vitae, circa 1960s (Box-folder 20: 16)
- Fragment of a bibliography, circa 1980s (Box-folder 20: 17)
- Western Hemisphere Conference on Economic and Social Order program and invitations, 1984 (Box-folder 20: 18)